Guide to the New-York Historical Society Museum Department Records 1765, 1830-2018 NYHS-RG 20
New-York Historical Society
- Series II. Exhibitions, 1941-2018; 167874; 74.08 Linear feet
  - Subseries II.A. General Files, 1941-2018; 168540; 62.25 Linear feet
    - Treasury of the Past (12 folders), 1995; 170129 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 1-12)
      Includes files related to the exhibition of N-YHS collection highlights that was installed to mark the re-opening of the N-YHS galleries. "Treasures," "Treasury," and "Treasures of the Past" are common shorthand names for the exhibition used in these and other files. Includes color slides of the installation.
    - Inventory / Christian Boltanski (2 folders), 1995; 170130 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 13-14)
    - Who Was Pocahontas?, 1995; 170131 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 15)
      Includes only color slides of the installation.
    - You Are Here: Perspectives on New York From the Map Collection of N-YHS (9 folders), 1995; 170135 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 16-24)
    - Clement Clark Moore and A Visit From St. Nicholas (2 folders), 1995; 170136 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 25-26)
    - Creating Fame, 1995; 170138 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 27)
    - Becoming Eleanor Roosevelt: The Early New York Years, 1996; 178870 (Offsite-box 273, Volume 1)
      Includes comments book only.
    - Tiffany Glass (6 folders), 1996?; 170139 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 28-33)
      This set of folders includes various documents, principally from the 1980s-1990s, related to Tiffany lamps and glass, apparently in connection with a 1996 installation. One folder includes education material for in-gallery use with grade school childen.
    - New York: Then & Now, Upper West Side, 1996; 170140 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 34)
      Includes only the comments book.
    - Child Rearing in New York (2 folders), 1996; 170141 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 35-36)
      Appears to be only a proposed exhibition.
    - Militant Metropolis: New York City and the Spanish-American War, 1998; 170142 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 37)
    - Treasures from Mount Vernon: George Washington Revealed, 1998; 170143 (Offsite-box 210, Folder 38)
    - The Italians of New York: Five Centuries of Struggle & Achievement (8 of 16 folders), 1999; 170144 (Offsite-box 211, Folder 1-8)
    - The Italians of New York: Five Centuries of Struggle & Achievement (8 of 16 folders), 1999; 170145 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 1-8)
    - Winter in New York, 1999; 170146 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 9)
    - Times Square: A Century in Photographs (5 folders), 2000; 170147 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 10-14)
    - Jenny Lind: The Swedish Nightingale in America (7 folders), 2000; 170148 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 15-21)
    - Audubon: The Birds of Winter (6 folders), 2000; 170149 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 22-27)
      Some of the documents refer to a different title, which might be a different exhibition, Audubon in Charleston.
    - Jesse Tarbox Beals: On Assignment (6 folders), 2000; 170150 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 28-33)
    - Fit for a King / Conservation of the Louis XVI Chair (7 folders), 2000; 170151 (Offsite-box 212, Folder 34-40)
      Includes color slides of the installation and color contact sheets and negatives of the conservation work.
    - New York on the Brink: The City's Fiscal Crisis of the 1970s (7 folders), 2000; 170152 (Offsite-box 213, Folder 1-7)
    - Without Sanctuary: Lynching Photography in America (10 folders), 2000; 170153 (Offsite-box 213, Folder 8-17)
    - Without Sanctuary: Lynching Photography in America. Oversize, 2000; 170154 (Offsite-box 273, Volume 2)
      Includes the comments book.
    - Magnum: Our Turning World: Photographs (11 folders), 2000; 170155 (Offsite-box 213, Folder 18-28)
    - Stork Club (10 folders), 2000; 170156 (Offsite-box 213, Folder 29-38)
    - New York Inside Out (13 folders), 2000; 170157 (Offsite-box 214, Folder 1-13)
    - Manhattan Contrasts: 20th Century Paintings of New York from the Collection of N-YHS (3 folders), 2000; 170158 (Offsite-box 214, Folder 14-16)
    - Inventing the Skyline: The Architecture of Cass Gilbert (9 folders), 2000; 170159 (Offsite-box 214, Folder 17-25)
      Includes color slides of the installation and two comment books.
    - American Art Posters of the 1890s (7 folders), 1999-2000; 170162 (Offsite-box 214, Folder 26-32)
      Includes documents related to the exhibition of N-YHS's posters at the Cincinnati Art Museum (1999), including color slides, and later (2000) exhibition at N-YHS. Some documents specifically refer to the Strobridge Lithographing Company Poster Collection, which may or may not be a different exhibition.
    - Looking at History, 2000; 170163 (Offsite-box 214, Folder 33-35)
    - Intimate Friends: Thomas Cole, Asher Durand and William Cullen Bryant (8 folders), 2000; 170214 (Offsite-box 215, Folder 1-8)
      Includes color slides of objects and installation. Also includes color slides of Recent Acquisitions: Juan Pliego, Craft Silversmith and of the hallway, stairs and galleries found with the Intimate Friends slides.
    - Eye of the Storm: The Civil War Sketches of Robert K. Sneden (10 folders), 2000; 170215 (Offsite-box 215, Folder 9-18)
    - Pray For Me: Letters & Diaries from American Wars (4 folders), 2000; 170216 (Offsite-box 215, Folder 19-22)
    - Remedies for Old Age / Exhibitions at Pfizer, Inc. (6 folders), 1998-2000; 170217 (Offsite-box 215, Folder 23-28)
    - Elder Grace: The Nobility of Aging / Chester Higgins, Jr. (12 folders), 2000; 170218 (Offsite-box 215, Folder 29-40)
    - The Changing Face of Liberty: Female Allegories of America (7 folders), 2000; 170232 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 1-7)
    - Advertising Drama, 2001; 170233 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 8)
    - New Eyes: Art by N-YHS High School Students, 2001; 170252 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 9)
    - The Sight of Music: Prints from the Collection of Reba and Dave Williams (7 folders), 2001; 170244 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 10-16)
    - Choosing to Participate: Facing History & Ourselves (7 folders), 2001; 170245 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 17-23)
    - Walk About: Past & Present Views of New York (8 folders), 2001; 170246 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 24-31)
    - Nightwalks: Irwin Silver (4 folders), 2001; 170247 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 32-35)
    - Out of Time: Designs for the 20th Century Future (6 folders), 2001; 170248 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 36-41)
    - Against the Storm: Images of Lighthouses from the Collections of N-YHS (4 folders), 2001; 170249 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 42-45)
    - Independence and Its Enemies in New York (6 folders), 2001; 170250 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 46-51)
    - Up on the Roof: The Culture of New York City Rooftops (7 of 18), 2001; 170251 (Offsite-box 216, Folder 52-58)
    - Up on the Roof: The Culture of New York City Rooftops (11 of 18), 2001; 170253 (Offsite-box 217, Folder 1-11)
      Most of the files for this exhibition in this box are the working research files of Kathleen Hulser.
    - Up on the Roof: The Culture of New York City Rooftops. Oversize, 2001; 170254 (Box 274, Folder 8)
      Includes oversize photographs; the folder is labeled as "unclear if used in exhibit."
    - In Memoriam (9/11 Memorial), 2001; 170255 (Offsite-box 217, Folder 12)
    - New York September 11 by Magnum Photographers, 2001; 170256 (Offsite-box 217, Folder 13)
    - Luman Reed Gallery, 2000-2001; 170257 (Offsite-box 217, Folder 14)
      Includes various documents related to the use or possible use of the Luman Reed Gallery for exhibitions.
    - Flophouse: Life on the Bowery (6 folders), 2001; 170303 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 1-6)
    - Exhibition Proposals (Unrealized), circa 2001-2004; 170304 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 7)
    - The Rosenbergs Reconsidered: The Death Penalty in the Cold War Era (4 folders), 2001; 170305 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 8-11)
    - Manhattan Unfurled, 2001; 170306 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 12)
    - The British in New York Since 1770, 2001; 170307 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 13)
    - Family Matters: Century-Old New York City Businesses (9 folders), 2002; 170308 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 14-22)
      Includes color slides of the installation. Includes 7 CDs labelled overall as "Master CDs," with logos, blow-ups, scrapbook, and other unclear matter.
    - September 11: One Year Later, 2002; 170309 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 23)
    - World Trade Center Monument (Research File), circa 2002; 170310 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 24)
    - Reading Uncle Tom's Image: A Reconsideration of Harriet Beecher Stowe's 150 Year-Old Character & His Legacy (4 of 13 folders), 2002; 170311 (Offsite-box 218, Folder 25-28)
      The bulk of the Reading Uncle Tom files appear to be those of public historian/researcher Kathleen Hulser.
    - Reading Uncle Tom's Image (9 of 13 folders), 2002; 170312 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 1-9)
    - Me, Myself & Infrastructure, 2002; 170313 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 10)
    - Building the Flatiron: The Centenary of a New York Icon, 2002; 170314 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 11)
    - Presidential Manuscript Treasures Revolving Exhibition, 2002; 170322 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 12)
    - Degrees of Latitude: Mapping Colonial America, 2002; 170315 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 13)
    - Life on the Lapel, 2002; 170316 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 14)
    - Freedom: A History of U.S., 2002; 170317 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 15)
    - Seat of Empire: Napoleon's Armchair from Malmaison to Manhattan, 2002; 170318 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 16)
    - Course of Empire: Thomas Cole and the Hudson River School Tradition of Landscape Painting (4 folders), 2003; 170323 (Offsite-box 219, Folder 17-20)
    - Enterprising Women: 250 Years of American Business, 2003; 170437 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 1)
    - Three Women Photographers, 2003; 170438 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 2)
      Includes only a services agreement with a consulting curator.
    - African American Masters: Highlights from the Smithsonian American Art Museum, 2003; 170439 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 3)
    - Telling Lives Kiosk, 2003; 170440 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 4)
      Also referred to as the LifeTimes project. The file also has a seemingly unrelated draft budget for the Madison Square Garden 125th Anniversary exhibition (planned for 2004).
    - Remembering the Forgotten Ones: Selections from the Milton Rogovin Collection, 2003; 170441 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 5)
    - Bella Landauer: Collector of Enterprise, 2003; 170442 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 6)
    - Children at Risk: Protecting New York City's Youths, 2003; 170447 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 7)
    - Recovery: The World Trade Center Recovery Operation at Fresh Kills, 2003; 170451 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 8)
    - Home Sewn / Pins & Needles: Sewing Crafts & Trades in New York, 2003; 170452 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 9)
    - Ann Zane Shanks: Behind the Lens, 2003; 170453 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 10)
    - Petropolis: A Social History of Urban Animal Companions (7 of 10 folders), 2003; 170457 (Offsite-box 220, Folder 11-17)
      Includes the research files.
    - Petropolis: A Social History of Urban Animal Companions (3 of 10 folders), 2003; 170458 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 1-3)
    - If Elected: Campaigning for the Presidency / Campaigns on Cotton, 2004; 170454 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 4)
      Some documents for these election-themed exhibitions appear to have been carried forward to the files of a 2009 exhibition If Elected: the Game of American Politics; see those folders below.
    - From the Classroom to the World: Hine, Ulmann, Strand, Arbus, and the Ethical Culture Fieldston School, 2004; 170455 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 5)
    - Times Square Centennial, 2004; 170456 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 6)
    - Radical Hospitality, 2004; 170459 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 7)
    - Treasures (Rotations), circa 2004; 170460 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 8)
    - Around Town Underground: The NYC Subway in Prints From the Collection of Reba & Dave Williams, 2004; 170461 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 9)
    - Birds of Central Park: Audubon's Watercolors, 2003; 170462 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 10)
    - The General Slocum and Little Germany (10 folders), 2004; 170463 (Offsite-box 221, Folder 11-20)
      Includes the research files of public historian Kathleen Hulser.
    - Tiffany Window Installation. Oversize, 2004; 171026 (Box 274, Folder 2)
      Includes material from designer Stephen Saitas concerning installation of The Good Shepherd window panels.
    - Alexander Hamilton: The Man Who Made Modern America (11 folders), 2004; 170549 (Offsite-box 222, Folder 1-11)
      Includes the Acoustiguide scripts and audio CDs for the both the adult and children's tours.
    - Nature and the American Vision: The Hudson River (3 folders), 2005; 170550 (Offsite-box 222, Folder 12-14)
    - Hudson River Travel, 2005; 170743 (Offsite-box 222, Folder 15)
    - Hudson River Rotations, 2006; 170746 (Offsite-box 222, Folder 16)
    - Audubon's Aviary (2 folders), 2006; 170556 (Offsite-box 222, Folder 17-18)
      Includes the press kit for the exhibition, the second of a planned five part annual Audubon exhibition. The kit includes a CD of images.
    - Slavery in New York (11 folders), 2005; 170552 (Offsite-box 223, Folder 1-11)
      Includes comment books and CD of "selected media presentations."
    - Slavery in New York. Oversize, 2005; 171031 (Box 274, Folder 9)
      Includes the guide to the exhibition, in the form of a copy of the Amsterdam News.
    - New York Divided: Slavery & The Civil War (8 folders), 2006; 170553 (Offsite-box 224, Folder 1-8)
      Many of the records refer to this exhibition as Slavery 2 or Slavery II. Includes publicity material with a CD and a comments book.
    - New York Divided: Slavery & The Civil War. Oversize, 2006; 171032 (Box 274, Folder 9)
      Includes the guide to the exhibition, in the form of a copy of the New York Post.
    - Legacies: Contemporary Artists Reflect on Slavery (7 of 16 folders), 2006; 170554 (Offsite-box 224, Folder 9-15)
      Includes comments book and a 10 minute DVD of the installation.
    - Legacies: Contemporary Artists Reflect on Slavery (9 of 16 folders), 2006; 170551 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 1-9)
    - Finding Priscilla's Children: The Roots and Branches of Slavery (5 folders), 2006; 170753 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 10-15)
    - Historical Fictions: Edward Lamson Henry's Paintings of the Past and Present (4 folders), 2006; 170754 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 16-19)
    - Viktor Schreckengost's 100th Birthday, 2006; 170755 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 20)
    - Gilded Age Sculptures (Lower Level), 2006; 170756 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 21)
      Includes CD of installation images.
    - Cafe Corridor, Lower Level, Checklist, 2006; 170757 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 22)
    - Winter Wonderland (Lower Level), 2006; 170758 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 23)
    - Suspicious Truths: Politics & the Press in American History, 2006; 170759 (Offsite-box 225, Folder 24)
    - Group Dynamics: Family Portraits & Scenes of Everyday Life at N-YHS (4 folders), 2006; 170760 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 1-4)
      Includes CDs of images
    - Elegy in the Dust: September 11th and the Chelsea Jeans Memorial (6 folders), 2006; 170555 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 5-10)
    - Here Is New York: Remembering 9/11 (6 folders), 2007; 170561 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 11-16)
    - Zouaves (in Print Room Corridor), 2007; 170557 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 17)
    - Carry Me Home: Dispatches from the Civil War, 2007; 170761 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 18)
    - The Confectionary States of America, 2007; 170558 (Offsite-box 226, Folder 19)
      Also referred to simply as "Sugar," this was a self-guided tour through the Henry Luce III Center for the Study of American Culture.
    - Kindred Spirits: Asher B. Durand and the American Landscape (5 folders), 2007; 170559 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 1-5)
      These files appear to relate to outgoing loans for an exhibition at other institutions. Nonetheless, there may be documents here related to the Durand exhibition held at N-YHS around the same time (see next entry).
    - The World of Asher B. Durand: The Artist in Antebellum New York (3 folders), 2007; 170560 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 6-8)
      See also the previous entry for the Kindred Spirits exhibition.
    - Life's Pleasures: The Ashcan Artists' Brush with Leisure (7 folders), 2007; 170564 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 9-15)
      Includes the press kit with CDs of images.
    - Audubon's Aviary: Natural Selection, 2007; 170563 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 16)
      Includes the press kit for the third of a five part annual Audubon exhibition.
    - John B. Snook: Architect of New York's Downtown Streetscape, 2007; 170711 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 17)
    - A New Light on Tiffany: Clara Driscoll & the Tiffany Girls (23 of 52 folders), 2007; 170562 (Offsite-box 228, Folder 1-23)
      Includes CDs of images and audio soundtracks, and comment books. Includes extensive files on the traveling aspect of the exhibition, especially in the following two boxes.
    - A New Light on Tiffany: Clara Driscoll & the Tiffany Girls (22 of 52 folders), 2007; 170762 (Offsite-box 229, Folder 1-22)
    - A New Light on Tiffany: Clara Driscoll & the Tiffany Girls (7 of 52 folders), 2007; 170763 (Offsite-box 230, Folder 1-7)
    - French Founding Father: Lafayette's Return to America (11 of 71 folders), 2007; 170708 (Offsite-box 230, Folder 8-18)
    - French Founding Father: Lafayette's Return to America (21 of 71 folders), 2007; 170709 (Offsite-box 231, Folder 1-21)
      Includes a DVD of Lafayette: The Lost Hero. Dated May 21, 2009, with a TRT of 1:24:00,this is a "rough cut," presumably of the PBS show of the same name released in 2010.
    - French Founding Father: Lafayette's Return to America (39 of 71 folders), 2007; 170764 (Offsite-box 232, Folder 1-39)
    - Nation at the Crossroads: New York Debates the Constitution (3 folders), 2008; 170765 (Offsite-box 227, Folder 18-20)
    - Drawn by New York: Six Centuries of Watercolors & Drawings at N-YHS (13 folders), 2008; 170716 (Offsite-box 233, Folder 1-13)
    - If Elected: The Game of American Politics (4 folders), 2004, 2008; 170766 (Offsite-box 233, Folder 14-17)
      The files also include documents from an earlier (2004) election-themed exhibition Campaigns on Cotton.
    - Woven Splendor from Timbuktu to Tibet: Exotic Rugs and Textiles from New York Collectors (10 folders), 2008; 170767 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 1-10)
    - Allure of the East: Orientalism in New York (3 folders), 2008; 170768 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 11-13)
    - Victor Prevost: Early Photographer of New York, 2008; 170769 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 14)
    - Plague in Gotham / Cholera 1832, 2008; 170770 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 15)
    - Audubon's Aviary: Portraits of Endangered Species, 2008; 170714 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 16)
      Includes publicity material with a CD.
    - A New President Takes Command: FDR's First Hundred Days (3 folders), 2008; 170715 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 17-19)
      Includes CDs with object images.
    - Grant and Lee in War and Peace (18 folders), 2008; 170713 (Offsite-box 235, Folder 1-18)
      Includes CDs of publicity material and a teen audio tour.
    - FDR's Brain Trust and the Beginning of the New Deal, 2009; 170771 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 20)
    - Landmarks of New York (2 folders), 2009; 170777 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 21-22)
    - Colonial Portraits, 2009; 170778 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 23)
    - John Brown: The Abolitionist and His Legacy (2 folders), 2009; 170779 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 24-25)
    - Ariadne: The Great American Nude, 2009; 170780 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 26)
    - Luce Rotations (Audubon), 2009; 170781 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 27)
    - Taking the Oath: The First Presidential Inauguration, 2009; 170782 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 28)
    - Intimate Lincoln / Low Light Lincoln, 2009; 170783 (Offsite-box 234, Folder 29)
    - Dutch New York Between East & West: The World of Margrieta van Varick (3 folders), 2009; 170784 (Offsite-box 235, Folder 19-21)
    - Lincoln and New York (17 of 29 folders), 2009; 170712 (Offsite-box 236, Folder 1-17)
    - Lincoln and New York (12 of 29 folders), 2009; 170785 (Offsite-box 237, Folder 1-12)
    - Lincoln and New York. Oversize, 2009; 171025 (Box 274, Folder 1)
      Includes two mounted posters and two mounted photographs of publicity signage.
    - Breakthrough: The Dramatic Story of the Discovery of Insulin (15 folders), 2010; 170786 (Offsite-box 238, Folder 1-15)
    - Breakthrough: The Dramatic Story of the Discovery of Insulin. Oversize, 2010; 171028 (Box 274, Folder 5)
      Includes the exhibition poster, signed by N-YHS staff.
    - Nueva York (13 of 56 folders), 2010; 170717 (Offsite-box 239, Folder 1-13)
      Includes Marci Reaven's research notes, CDs of the gallery, a CD of a film by Steeplechase Films, and more.
    - Nueva York (14 of 56 folders), 2010; 170718 (Offsite-box 240, Folder 1-14)
    - Nueva York (16 of 56 folders), 2010; 170787 (Offsite-box 241, Folder 1-16)
    - Nueva York (13 of 56 folders), 2010; 170788 (Offsite-box 242, Folder 1-13)
    - Nueva York. Oversize, 2010; 171027 (Box 274, Folder 4)
      Includes the Proclamation from the Council of the City of New York naming April 29, 2010, as New York Historical Society and El Museo del Barrio Appreciation Day.
    - The Grateful Dead: Now Playing at N-YHS (10 folders), 2010; 170789 (Offsite-box 243, Folder 1-10)
    - The Grateful Dead: Now Playing at N-YHS. Oversize, 2010; 171057 (Drawer 12A-B10, Folder 17)
      Includes one poster.
    - Great Hall Exhibition / New York Rising: New York and the Founding of the United States, 2011; 170719 (Offsite-box 243, Folder 11)
    - Revolution! The Atlantic World Reborn, 2011; 171030 (Box 274, Folder 7)
      Includes the Design Control Package (May 2011) and the invitation for the re-opening of the N-YHS galleries (November 2011)
    - Treasures of American Folk Art: Elie Nadelman, Pioneer Collector, 2011; 170720 (Offsite-box 243, Folder 12)
      Includes early concept papers for a possible exhibition.
    - Howard Thain, 2012; 170721 (Offsite-box 243, Folder 13)
      Includes only a CD labeled as having 4 selected scenes from "Tite (?) Crowd."
    - Smallpox, Vaccination & Civil Liberties in New York, 2012; 170722 (Offsite-box 243, Folder 14)
      Includes only a DVD of a video, possibly used in the exhibition.
    - Stories in Silver: Four Centuries of Silver in New York (9 folders), 2012; 170728 (Offsite-box 244, Folder 1-9)
      Includes CD of the audio tour and a "Smithers video," presumably used in the exhibition.
    - The Vietnam War: 1945-1975, 2017-2018 (Offsite-box 277, Folder -)
      Scope and Contents
      Includes the 15 comment books from the exhibition, a 337 page unedited typescript of the comments, and the edited selections presented on-line at vietnamwar.nyhistory.org. (At present no other records about the exhibition have been transferred to the archives.)
  - Subseries II.B. Audubon Traveling Exhibition, 1984-1996; 170792; 4.17 Linear feet
    The subseries is roughly arranged by topic. Files related to specific venues are first, followed by more general exhibition planning and logistical files, object lists, funding, general correspondence, catalogue arrangements, and other product development.
    The subseries includes the records related to the 1990s traveling exhibition John James Audubon: The Watercolors for The Birds of America. The exhibition included about 100 of N-YHS's Audubon works and was the first time N-YHS had ever allowed the watercolors to travel. The exhibition venues were the National Gallery of Art, Museum of Fine Arts Boston, Detroit Institute of Arts, Art Institute of Chicago, Museum of Fine Arts Houston, Memphis Brooks Museum of Art, Seattle Art Museum, and the Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco.